LUKEMITCHELL

CURRICULUM VITAE

Updated March 22rd 2016

ABOUT ME

A software developer, UI designer, technology consultant and a blue-sky thinker. I've worked as a cryptocurrency developer for a number of small FinTech startups. A creative thinker, I'm self motivated and an experienced team leader. I've developed a hobby operating system, several cryptocurrencies and a magnetic stylus for guiding the user as they point. I speak basic German.

I enjoy travelling, climbing, taking photographs and yoga. I've cycled 2400 kilometers across the Alps, and I've hitchhiked across Europe. I'm an environmentalist, a climate-change activist and a keen vegetarian cook.

You can find me online at www.lukemitchell.co and my open-source projects at www.github.com/lukem512. I'm on Linked In at www.github.com/lukem512. I'm on Linked In <a href="https://w

EMPLOYMENT

Technology Consultant

February 2014 to date

I am currently working as a freelance consultant, specialising in developing cryptocurrency applications for FinTech startups. I have worked with other developers and, latterly, as a technical adviser to launch products including a gold-backed blockchain, an encrypted messenger with an integrated wallet and an array of supporting software. My recent clients include The Real Asset Co. and StartJOIN Holdings Ltd.

Skills: Software design, UI, JavaScript, C++, web, mobile, cryptocurrency

Cambridge Consultants: Technology Scholar

September 2010 to September 2012 (1 year, 3 months)

I spent a year working as an intern with Cambridge Consultants before starting my degree. During this time I was a member of several internal development teams including an intern-led project developing a 'whitespace' WiFi network. I returned the following summer to work for the business following my first year of University. During this time I worked on a variety of client projects including a testing framework for the Highways Agency, a UI mockup for Novartis and a survey framework. During my time there I billed more client hours than any previous Technology Scholar.

Skills: Software development, project organisation, C#, PHP, Linux, wireless

ARM: IT Support Placement

June 2008 to August 2008 (3 months)

I spent two months working as an intern with ARM following a two week work experience placement. During my time with the company I diagnosed hardware faults, scripted upgrades and prepared a Linux distribution for use within the company.

Skills: Hardware diagnostics, Linux

VOLUNTEERING

Hungry Caterpillar Food Co-op

September 2012 to date

I am the president of a student not-for-profit co-operative. The organisation helps students make ethical food choices by providing a weekly pop-up shop selling organic and fairtrade produce, sourced from local suppliers. The co-operative has dozens of members and the organisation requires social media management, stock-taking and charisma. We were awarded the Volunteers for Food award at the Bristol Green Volunteering Awards in 2016.

Callington Road Psychiatric Hospital

2013

I have volunteered for an organisation that visits a psychiatric hospital to talk to patients, play games with them and generally alleviate the monotony of hospital life. I found this to be a challenging and moving experience that I enjoyed immensely.

Other

I have volunteered at various projects including Food Cycle, the University of Bristol Botanical Gardens, the Bristol University Sustainability Team and the COP21 climate march. I have helped prepare food for a large number of people, performed website upgrades and acted as a steward.

PUBLICATIONS

Force Attraction Pen: A Haptic Pen with Variable Attraction Force, Burnside, Elgar, Healer, Hill, Ioannidis, Mitchell, Worgan and Roudaut. In Proceedings of CHI EA'16. Late Breaking Work. To appear 2016.

EDUCATION

MEng Computer Science

University of Bristol July 2016

Final project: "Study into the effects of social pledges on the motivation of individuals performing a task"

A level Computer Science, Maths, Philosophy (Grades A, A, B)

AS level Electronics (Grade A)

Hills Road Sixth Form, Cambridge June 2010

REFEREES

Dr. Chris Preist

Reader in Sustainability and Computer Systems University of Bristol chris.preist@bristol.ac.uk Dr. Julian Gough

Professor of Bioinformatics University of Bristol julian.gough@bristol.ac.uk Jon Edgcombe

Group Leader
Cambridge Consultants Ltd.
jon.edgcombe@cambridgeconsultants.com